在这个时代，我们所有人都非常依赖互联网。
In this day and age, we've all become pretty much dependent on the internet.
我们通过互联网使用APP与朋友和家人聊天，导航去处，网上购物，
We use it to connect with friends and family, to figure out where we're going, to purchase
更有甚者依赖它进行工作和就学。
things, and some of us are even dependent on it to get to work and school with apps.
例如Uber和Lyft。
like Uber and Lyft.
但是，如果整个互联网突然关闭的话会发生什么？
But what would happen if the entire internet suddenly shut down?
长话短说，产生混乱！
Long story short - It would be chaos!
股市将会关闭，我们将无法访问银行或使用银行卡付款，
The stock market would shut down, we wouldn't be able to access our banks or pay with our
GPS导航系统将停止工作，并且你也无法观看任何优秀的B站视频
cards, GPS would stop working, and you wouldn't be able to watch any great YouTube videos
就像这个。
like this one.
幸运的是，在偶发性WiFi中断的情况，我们大多数人都不必拥有
Thankfully, outside of the occasional Wi-Fi outage, most of us haven't had to experience
如此的经历。
anything like this.
但是，由于某一个人的无意所为，一整个国家曾经体验过
However, thanks to the accidental handiwork of just one man, an entire country once went
上述水平的灾难状况。
through that exact disaster-level situation.
那这个男人是谁？
So who was this man?
他是如何切断整个国家的互联网连接的？
How did he knock out an entire country's internet connection?
造成的结果是什么？
And what happened as a result?
让我们来深入了解一下。
Let's dive right in to find out.
早在2016年11月，利比里亚的手机和互联网提供商Cellcom的一名员工向
Back in November of 2016, a man named Daniel Kaye was approached by an employee of the
一位名叫丹尼尔凯伊（Daniel Kaye）的男子提出了一个很有吸引力的提议。
Liberian cell phone and internet provider Cellcom with a very interesting offer.
每月付10,000美元让凯伊尽可能地对Cellcom的主要竞争对手Lonestar的服务和
$10,000 a month for Kaye to do as much damage as humanly possible to Cellcom's main rival,
声誉造成损害。
Lonestar's, service and reputation.
那么，为什么丹尼尔凯伊会得到如此庞大的工作呢？
So why would Daniel Kaye be approached for such a huge job?
凯伊，一个28岁的英国人，来自埃格姆（Egham, ）市，是一个完全
Well, Kaye, a then 28-year-old British man originally from the city of Egham, was a completely
自学成才的黑客，并开始提供非法的黑客入侵服务。
self-taught hacker who had begun offering illicit hacking services.
这位Cellcom的员工可能希望从他们的最大竞争对手那里争取尽可能多的客户，
The Cellcom employee, likely hoping to take as many customers from their large rival as
于是通过风谲云诡的暗网寻求凯伊的帮助。
possible, sought out Kaye's help through the elusive dark web.
在接下来的几周中，丹尼尔凯伊开始规划他的黑客活动。
Over the next few weeks, Daniel Kaye began planning his hack.
他决定使用一种久经考验的入侵方法，这种方法已经在数千次攻击中
He decided he would use a tried and true hacking method that had been used for decades
使用了数十年：DDOS。
in thousands of attacks: DDOS.
DDOS代表分布式拒绝服务。
DDOS standing for Distributed Denial of Service.
基本上就是黑客同时发送大量的客户端请求访问服务器，
Basically, it means that a hacker sends so many requests to enter a server at once, that
以至于服务器无法处理并崩溃。
the server can't handle them all and crashes.
当一家公司发布全新的限量版商品，
The same type of this can accidentally happen when a company releases brand new, limited
或者备受追捧的音乐会开始售票，数百万人试图同时登录一个网站时，
edition merchandise, or when highly sought-after concert tickets go on sale and millions of
此类情况可能会发生。
people try to log onto a site at once.
为了发动这次对利比里亚通讯商Lonestar的袭击，凯伊有一个
In order to launch this attack on Lonestar in Liberia, Kaye had an elaborate plan in
周密的计划。
mind.
具有讽刺意味的是，他发现一个安全摄像头品牌
He had found a brand security cameras, ironically enough, themselves
本身就存在一个可以利用的安全弱点。
had a security weakness that could be exploited.
使用一串称为“ Mirai＃14”的代码和命令。基本上是一些黑客手段中的
Using a string of code and commands known as "Mirai #14"， basically some hacking mumbo
巨无霸，凯伊接管了网络摄像头，并于2016年11月3日启动所有摄像头
jumbo, Kaye took control of the web-connected cameras, and on November 3rd, 2016,
同时尝试访问Lonestar的服务器。
sent themall to simultaneously try and access Lonestar's servers.
现在，你应该了解下利比里亚当时的互联网
Now, there's something you should know about the internet connection in Liberia at the
连接情况。
time.
当时互联网和手机服务提供商的数量非常有限，
There were a very limited number of internet and cell phone service providers back then,
所以该国的大部分流量都是通过Lonestar或Cellcom提供的网络进行的，
so most of the traffic in the country went through either Lonestar or Cellcom networks,
并且大西洋电缆的连接非常有限，这意味着向Lonestar发动的攻击
and alongside having a very limited Atlantic Cable connection, this meant that an attack
可能会使所有通过利比里亚的互联网请求
on Lonestar could mean that all the requests for internet moving through Liberia wouldn't
都无法完成。
have any way to be completed.
摄像机一经触发就使Lonestar的网络不堪重负，变得
As soon as the cameras started being used to overwhelm the Lonestar network, it
不稳定，在某些地方甚至直接停止服务。
began to struggle, and in some places even shut down.
但是凯伊认为自己没有足够的火力，因此，他还试图利用德国电信（deutsche telekom）
However Kaye didn't think he had enough firepower, so he attempted to also create some
在德国国家基站基础设施的另一个安全漏洞，
more DDoS bots by exploiting another security flaw in the national infrastructure
制造更多的DDoS进攻节点。
of cell towers in Germany, set up by Deutsche Telekom.
此时，Lonestar邀请了网络安全专家，但是为时已晚。
At this point, Lonestar called in cyber security experts, but it was too late.
侵入已经失控了。
The hack had already gotten out of control.
由于利比里亚互联网流量的很大一部分依赖于Lonestar建立的基础设施，
Due to the fact that a large portion of Liberia's internet traffic was dependent on infrastructure
在接下来Lonestar受到攻击的两天里，
set up by Lonestar, for the next two days, while Lonestar was under attack, internet
全国的互联网用户发现他们无法打电话，
users across the country found that they were unable to make phone calls or even access
甚至无法上网。
the internet.
丹尼尔凯伊无意地切断了整个国家的互联网连接。
Without even meaning to, Daniel Kaye had knocked out an entire country's internet
这是历史上第一次有人这样做，这完全就是
connection. This was the first time anyone had managed to do this in history, and it
意外造成的。
was entirely by accident.
2017年2月，经过调查，凯伊因涉嫌实施重大黑客攻击
In February of 2017, following an investigation, Kaye was arrested under suspicion of having
而被捕。
committed the major hack.
在被捕后，凯伊也被引渡到德国面临指控，
Following his arrest, Kaye was extradited to Germany to face charges there as well,
因为在试图利用德国电信网络资源的过程中，他还成功地
as during his attempt to use resources from the Deutsche Telekom network he had also
切断了该公司逾12.4万名客户的互联网连接。
succeeded in knocking out the internet connection of more than 124,000 of their customers.
在那里，他也承认了这些指控，尽管这些指控远没有他回到英国后
There too, he pled guilty to the charges, although they were far less severe than the
所面临的严重。
ones he faced when he returned to the UK.
一经德国将凯伊送回英国，根据1990年英国制定的计算机滥用法案，他承认了犯罪行为，
Once Germany sent Kaye back to his homeland, he pled guilty to crimes under the Computer
并承认拥有犯罪财产，即他为完成这一切而
Misuse Act of 1990 under UK law, as well as possession of criminal property, namely the
已经收到的10000美元。
10,000 dollars he had received in order to do all of this.
在调查过程中，人们发现，在攻击最严重的时候，凯伊在全世界
During the investigation, it was discovered that at the peak of the hack, Kaye had been
控制了100多万台设备，这一切都发生在他一直居住的
in control of over 1 million devices worldwide, all from the comfort of a vacation home in
塞浦路斯（Cyprus ）度假别墅里。
Cyprus he had been staying at.
凯伊的黑客攻击对Lonestar和整个利比里亚的影响之深远令人难以置信。
The effects of Kaye's hack on Lonestar, and Liberia as a whole, were incredibly far reaching.
他这样做让所有Lonestar的客户，实际上就是整个利比里亚的大多数人，
He had made it so that all of Lonestar's customers, and really most people across Liberia,
完全失去沟通或获取基本服务。
were totally unable to communicate with each other or access basic services.
由于遭到骇客入侵，这些客户中有相当一部分转而投向Lonestar的
As a result of the hack, a substantial number of these customers switched to Lonestar's
竞争者，其中就包括Cellcom，最终竟还是达到了目的。
competitors, including Cellcom, who at the end of the day, still got what they wanted.
丹尼尔·凯伊被判入狱32个月，这对于他给利比里亚国家造成的难以置信的破坏
Daniel Kaye was sentenced to serve 32 months in jail, a small price to pay for the incredible
来说算是很小的代价。
damage he caused to the nation of Liberia.
事实上，凯伊甚至可能从他的被捕中获得了一些好处，因为他的律师曾表示，
In fact, Kaye may have even gained some benefits from his arrest, as his lawyer has stated
自侵入发生以来，几家主要的科技公司已经与凯伊取得了联系，希望招募他来
that since the attack, several major tech companies have reached out to Kaye, wanting
使用自己的能力来造福而不是作恶。
to recruit him to use his powers for good instead of evil.
那么，如果你的国家的互联网突然中断，你会怎么办？
So what would you do if the internet suddenly went out in your entire country?
写在下方评论让我们知道吧。
Let us know down in the comments.
感谢收看！
Thanks for watching!